unfranchise.com 2012-05-02

# Market America Privacy Policy | Unfranchise Business

Your Market America Privacy Policy

We appreciate the trust you place in Market America, and we are committed to respecting your privacy and the security of your personal information. Our privacy policy describes the information we collect and how we use it.

Information We Collect

**
  1. Personal Information
**

To best serve your needs, we will, from time to time, collect certain information from you. The information we collect may include, without limitation, your name, address, telephone number, email address, corporate information, testimonial, credit card information and date of birth. Personal information will be collected at various times including, without limitation, when you:

  * Submit an Independent Distributor Application & Agreement
  * Register as a Preferred Customer
  * Apply to change the name or ownership of your Distributorship
  * Apply to be a Business Entity Distributorship
  * Enroll in or use Transfer Buy
  * Order or reorder products in person, by telephone, by mail or on our website
  * Write an e-mail or letter to Market America
  * Submit a product review, testimonial, power profile or personal success story to Market America
  * Order tickets to an event or seminar
  * Return an item or make an exchange
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event
  * Attend an event or seminar
  * Contact our customer service or product information departments
  * Register on our website
  * Order products and services from our partner stores

 ****
  1.  **Technical information collected and stored automatically**

When you visit the Site, we may store some or all of the following: the Internet address from which you accessed the Site, the date and time you visited the Site, whether you are a new or returning visitor, the page from which you exit the Site, what country you are visiting from (your network location), the Internet address of the web site from which you linked to the Site, the name of the file or words you searched for, items clicked on a page, and the browser and operating system used.

Using Information We Collect

We want to provide you with the best possible internet experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. Additionally, we want to make your experience as an Independent Distributor or Sales Representative a pleasant and successful one. In order to do this, we collect information that allows us to do the following, without limitation:

 ****
  1.  **Use of Personal Information**

  * Process your order
  * Provide the products and services you request
  * Partner with stores where you like to shop
  * Send you promotional offers
  * Identify the product and service preferences of you and your customers
  * Customize our communications to you
  * Provide information concerning products you have purchased for personal use or sale
  * Improve our product selection and customer service
  * Share your positive product testimonials and personal success stories with others
  * Enter into an Independent Distributor (or Sales Representative) relationship with you
  * Track and credit BV, IBV and cash back
  * Monitor your compliance with Market America rules and policies
  * Include your name, stories, testimonials, product reviews, power profiles, images, and commission and retail profit income information: 
    * in local and national newspapers, magazines or other media;
    * at events, on CDs, DVDs and other audios and videos, on websites and in publications and literature owned, operated or published by Market America or its affiliates or third parties;
    * in any other Market America communications to the field or others; and/or
    * as otherwise deemed useful or appropriate by Market America.

 ****
  1.  **Use of Technical Information**

This information is used to measure the number of visitors to the Site and to various sections of the Site, the percentage of visits that came from particular key word searches, the average time spent on the Site by visitors and the average number of page views by visitors. It may also be used to identify system performance or problem areas. We also use this information to help us develop the Site, analyze patterns of usage, and to make the site more useful. This information is not used for associating search terms or patterns of site navigation with individual users. The Site may periodically delete its web logs. We use third party analytics services to collect and analyze this data, and on occasion, we may provide this information to third party entities we contract with for the purpose of further analyzing website traffic.

 ****
  1.  **Use of Cookies**

Market America uses cookies on our websites. A cookie is a small data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies allow us to enhance, personalize and track your online experience, so that the information you receive is more relevant to you. This technology will allow you to move faster through our website once the information is in our database since you do not have to re-enter the same information or log in each time you enter the site.

Information We Share with Others and Your Privacy Rights

It is not a practice of Market America to sell, rent, or trade personal information. In order to service our Distributors, Sales Representatives and Preferred Customers, we share limited personal information with our Independent Distributors and affiliates. Market America's Independent Distributors are obligated to treat the information you supply with confidentiality. 

We share certain limited information with the partner stores where you shop. If you order products from Alice.com they will receive your order information, name, address, telephone number, age and gender, as well as any other information necessary to properly fulfill your order. Their treatment of your Personal Information will be governed by the terms of their Privacy Statement, which we will always provide for your review during checkout, when an Alice.com product is in your cart. Additionally, we contract with other companies to provide certain services, including without limitation credit card processing, IT consulting, printing, shipping, internet services, e-commerce, public and media relations. We make every effort to provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services. Generally, such companies are prohibited from sharing this information with anyone other than Market America or its Independent Distributors.

If you apply for the Market America credit card online and you live in the United States, you provide the financial information needed to process your application directly to Barclays Bank, the issuer and the administrator of the credit card program. Barclays Bank is a financial institution, independent of Market America. Barclays Bank has its own privacy and security policies, which you can review at [www.juniper.com](http://www.juniper.com/). Additionally, Barclays Bank is subject to the strict privacy regulations under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, 15 USC § 6801-6827.

If you apply for the Market America credit card online and you live in Canada, you provide the financial information needed to process your application directly to MBNA, the issuer and the administrator of the credit card program. MBNA is a financial institution, independent of Market America. MBNA has its own privacy and security policies, which you can review at [www.mbna.com/canada](http://www.mbna.com/canada).

On rare occasions, we may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, or when required by law to do so. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

How We Use Email

When you provide us your email address, we may send you emails necessary to process your order, respond to a request, provide customer service, promote products or services, or assist you in growing your business, inform you about products, services or promotional materials and assist you with the promotion of products and services to your customers. It is our intent to send promotional emails only to those persons who wish to receive them. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in our e-mails. 

Links to Other Sites

We provide links on our Web site to other sites. These sites operate independently of Market America and have established their own privacy and security policies. We encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.

Updating or Reviewing Your Information

You may review or update your Distributor information (name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card number, etc.) on this website ([www.unfranchise.com](http://www.unfranchise.com/)) under My Account, Distributor Profile. 

Security

Market America is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of information we collect, and we limit the information we provide to third parties.

When you make a purchase or submit an Independent Distributor Application & Agreement or other document on our web site, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. 

Privacy of Children on Our Web Site

Our Web site is not intended for use by anyone under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of 18. 

Policy Changes

From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post these changes in our website. We encourage you to review our privacy policy periodically.

Your Consent

By using Market America facilities and continuing to order products and services, you consent to the collection and use of your personal and technical information and cookies as detailed in this privacy policy.

Contact Us

We always welcome your questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at [privacy@marketamerica.com](mailto:privacy@marketamerica.com).

 **Updated January 30, 2012**
